Chapter 69

Beatdown

Sylphie hated herself. She was a really bad hawk and hadn’t done as she was told. Her mom and dad had repeatedly told her to be careful around those things called natural treasures, but she couldn’t hold herself back when she felt it. She hadn’t listened… and it had gotten them all killed.

She tried to run as they’d told her, but she couldn’t even do that! Another of those big eagles came and hurt her and made her fly back to her parents. Their own small eagle was jeering at her the entire time, being really stupid and rude.

After Mom and Dad used their super move, Sylphie thought things would be fine. They’d defeated the big eagle that Sylphie couldn’t beat on her own with a single hit and broke the barrier! She was sure the biggest eagle would be beaten too… but it had just fired a laser. It had sent Mom plummeting down, and it had hurt Dad badly.

Sylphie knew they needed help! She flew in and used her super talons, but it didn’t work. She was struck, and everything began spinning and hurting really badly, and Sylphie didn’t like it at all! A part of her knew she had to run—her parents wanted her to run—but she couldn’t just leave them. She did feel bad about her not returning to help protect Uncle, but she couldn’t just leave like that…

She cried a lot inside. She tried to get up and fight back. Dad attacked the biggest eagle but was hit another time. She got a really bad feeling and screeched for Dad to get away, but he couldn’t move… Was… was Dad going to die? Dad couldn’t die… could he? He and mom were so strong… Was the biggest eagle really so much stronger?

Her eyes opened wide, and she tried to get up as the big eagle was about to hit Dad again. She knew it couldn’t hit, but she couldn’t get up…

And then the eagle just stopped, and everything got even worse as she felt Uncle. He appeared a moment later and managed to catch the eagle by surprise, hitting it away.

Why? Why had Uncle come here? Mom and Dad were so hurt already… Dad wasn’t even moving… Not Uncle too…

No! He needed to run! She screamed to warn him to get away before the biggest eagle also decided to hurt Uncle! Sylphie couldn’t protect him right now, and it wasn’t fair that he also had to get hurt just because Sylphie had been bad… It wasn’t fair.

Yet he just picked her up and made her drink one of his not-so-smelly drinks. It spread warmth throughout her body, and she felt a lot better super fast. Uncle had also given Dad one, and they flew over and gave Mom one too. Mom was still not awake, but Sylphie could tell she would be fine.

Uncle put her down and patted her on the head.

"Please, just stay here," Uncle said.

Sylphie didn’t understand… Why stay when they had to run? Mom and Dad couldn’t beat the bad guy yet; they had to get away before it came back.

"You did well, mate. Now let me handle the rest," Uncle then said to dad, and Dad opened his eye and blinked slowly.

Dad didn’t seem scared? He just blinked with gratitude and seemed relieved. Happy.

She saw Uncle turn around… and he looked different from behind. The air around him was moving a bit weird, and he seemed very mad. Was he mad at Sylphie because she had been bad? No, he was mad at the biggest eagle...

Sylphie looked down towards the biggest eagle and was surprised. It looked back up at them, but it didn’t move. It just sat there. Staring. It looked almost scared. Why would the biggest eagle be scared of Uncle?

Were Dad and Mom right? Was Uncle actually super-duper strong?

She got her answer when he summoned a stick. A string-shooty stick.

Emotions were something Jake had been working on. Ever since the whole Abby-Donald Incident, Jake had always been mindful about keeping his emotions under control. He didn’t want to lose his cool or do something unintended in a moment where he got too emotional. His Bloodline made it difficult, but he had managed to cope his entire life, and he could cope now.

But there were still moments where he failed to hold it back. Perhaps times where his emotions were more than well placed. Moments where his unbridled rage was an acceptable response.

Today was one such day. A day where he didn’t need to hold back. He didn’t need to be mindful; he could release everything and have his target be the subject of that rage. Perhaps it was a cathartic and very healthy thing for Jake. He didn’t know; he just knew that holding himself back even long enough to gather the birds and give them potions was a challenge. But now that they were safe?

Jake summoned the new bow he had gotten from Sultan and drew the string. The bow sent fire mana down into the summoned arrow… and weakened it. He instantly detected the issues, but for now, it really wasn’t something he bothered fixing. He dispelled the arrow he had summoned—an explosive one—and summoned a stable one instead. That one just rejected the fire mana, making the enchantment do nothing.

A bit of poison was sprinkled on the arrow as Jake bit his lip and spat some blood on it—a new trick he’d thought of just now. Mainly because he wasn’t thinking much at all, but just wanted to savage that shitface of a bird who’d dared to hurt Sylphie, Hawkie, and Mystie.

He began channeling an Arcane Powershot, and that was when the Goldsun Eagle Prima below got out of its stupor. Of course, it was still under the influence of his presence. He didn’t bother analyzing it right now; he just knew the bird was unnerved. Then again, it wasn’t necessarily due to the presence; it could also just be that it was acutely aware.

Jake was stronger. From the moment his will appeared and his presence shrouded the valley, stopping not only the eagle’s body with Gaze but even the magic through the presence, it became apparent.

The Goldsun Eagle Prima was around the same tier as the Monkey Prima. No… slightly lower. At level 144, it was ten levels higher, but due to the difference in their tiers, it quite honestly wasn’t that much stronger than the Monkey Prima had been back then. And even if it was a little stronger, Jake was a lot stronger.

When he killed the Monkey Prima, he had been level 107. Now he was nearly twenty levels higher at 126. He had gotten skill upgrades, improved his poisons a whole lot, consumed elixirs, applied gear upgrades, and overall just grown in every single way. So while the fight against the Monkey Prima had been very even… this one wouldn’t be. It wouldn’t even truly be a fight.

Jake released his Arcane Powershot, and the entire side of the canyon he was standing on began collapsing. The Eagle Prima tried to dodge but was frozen by his Gaze once again. It erected a barrier that exploded when the arrow hit it, sending the huge bird tumbling back.

He didn’t let up, shooting another arrow and then another. He rapid-fired arrows that all split and pierced the stones the eagle tried to hide behind, many penetrating its body too. The Eagle Prima wasn’t weak enough to only be able to run and hide, however.

Its entire body began burning brighter with radiant light as it lit up like the sun. It flew upwards and spread its wings wide to send out a massive flare, clearly aiming to blind Jake. He felt his eyes burn but didn’t avert his gaze for even a moment. Compared to the pain the beast had subjected the hawks to, this was nothing.

Besides, it wasn’t like he truly needed his eyes. His Mark of the Avaricious Hunter had been on the eagle from the very first stomp, so even without his vision, he could keep up his assault. Not that the eagle could even burn his eyes enough. Perception seemed to somehow make even his borderline-melted eyes function without any issues.

The eagle above didn’t only aim to blind him, however. Instead, it began lighting up, and a massive amount of mana began condensing. It was clearly disturbed, and it decided to go all-out from the start. It dove down towards him like a miniature sun, the very air around it vibrating from the heat.

Jake summoned his scales and fired a fast Arcane Powershot up towards the eagle. Perhaps the eagle had hoped to evaporate the magical arrow before it could hit… but Jake’s stable arcane mana was far too, well, stable for that.

Blood spurted as the arrow pierced straight through the eagle and out the other side. It did nothing to stop its charge, however.

The massive, burning form crashed down onto Jake. His scales crackled from the heat, and he stopped breathing to not heat up his insides. He guessed the eagle didn’t want to fight a ranged battle with him. While that was a good choice… it didn’t make it a smart one.

Jake jumped and took a two-handed swing with all his might. The veins in his arms burned with energy as the eagle tried to avoid having its head caved in at the very last moment. It managed to adjust, but was still hit on the right wing and sent smashing into the ground below like a meteor—burning crater and all.

He didn’t let up but raised his foot. He stepped forward onto a mana platform not far from the eagle and, with one more step, arrived just in front of it. Jake summoned the scimitar and threw the long staff into the other, giving him a weapon in each hand.

One had to remember he didn’t even have his Nanoblade, as he hadn’t gone to get it and didn't even know if it was ready. Of his regular weapons, he only had the scimitar… and a certain item he had become fond of after the Altmar Census Golem.

The Pillar of Encumbrance smashed down where the eagle’s head had just been as the large bird transformed itself into a beam of light, much like Jake’s Shadow Vault. He held out his hand and nearly instantaneously threw a barrier of stable arcane mana in front of the eagle.

Like with his Shadow Vault, it could break through a barrier and take some damage. At least, it normally could. But Jake didn’t allow it to, as he focused his will on the barrier to stop the beast. It smashed into the wall and was sent reeling back from the impact, clearly confused at how robust the hastily constructed barrier was.

"You’re not running," Jake said as he took another step forward and appeared before the Eagle Prima again.

It fired a beam of sunlight down towards him, but he sidestepped and smashed it in the side with the Pillar. It tried to strike back with a talon swipe but ended up just getting a long and deep cut on its foot from the scimitar.

"Stop fighting," he said, kicking the beast many times larger than himself on the already-damaged wing. "This isn’t a fight. This is a beatdown."

The Eagle Prima looked down at him, afraid but still struggling. It knew it had fucked up. All it wanted to do was run… but there was no way in hell Jake would let that happen.

What followed wasn’t truly a fight. It was just Jake constantly running over the possibilities of the hawks dying in his head. He knew it was a risk. A constant one. It came with the territory of seeking more power, but that didn’t mean Jake liked it. Not at all.

Was beating what most would consider a boss monster half to death a logical or even reasonable response? No. No, it wasn’t. The world wasn’t reasonable to begin with. The Eagle Prima had merely committed the sin of pissing Jake off by going after one of the few things he would gladly kill to protect.

Hawkie had managed to stand up, his body was still slowly healing. His mate had also come to, and after the initial confusion, she joined him. They both stood on each side of their daughter, who observed the valley deep below.

Sylphie’s eyes were wide. She didn’t blink a single time, but just looked at what was going on below. It wasn’t a battle, but a slaughter—an utter display of dominance and power. Hawkie knew the human had stronger tools to defeat the eagle. He had used it in the beginning to initially wound it… but he didn’t use it now.

No, he got close. He met it in melee, as he wanted it to be personal. Hawkie could feel all this, as could Sylphie and Mystie. The emotions of the human were projected into his presence and weighed down on them, even from so far away. They sensed his anger, resentment, and even faint trace of reluctance over accepting what could have happened.

Hawkie shared a glance with his mate. They both knew it was clear… Their idea to create a possible technique to fight the human wasn't needed. Not only because the man clearly had no intentions of causing them any harm, but also because it was obvious how meaningless it would be.

The two of them had been weaker than the human when they initially met. Weaker, but not to the level of being utterly suppressed. When they both reached D-grade, they’d hoped to at least begin approaching his level, but it was now clear that the gap wasn’t closing, only widening.

They were both surprised at his power. The Eagle Prima displayed magic technique after magic technique that stumped the both of them, but the human crushed everything and simply smashed or cut the eagle again. It tried to fight him in a physical bout, but that proved even more meaningless. Its power meant nothing, and from the looks of it, it couldn’t even display its full might. It was scared and scrambling from the get-go. This was what surprised them the most. Not that he won, but that he dominated his foe so completely.

But the most surprised of them all was Sylphie. Hawkie and Mystie both knew their daughter had issues believing the human was powerful. It was understandable. No beast in their right mind would sit still for so long, doing nothing that seemed in any way related to growing more powerful. If it was absorbing energy from some natural treasure? Maybe. But he wasn’t even doing that.

The human could sit for so long playing with what Hawkie had learned was called a cauldron. He could create magical liquids like the one that had saved his life today, as well as the accursed toxins that were running through the body of the Eagle Prima.

For Sylphie to believe he was not a fighter made sense. Most beasts that were good at creation weren’t good at fighting, or at least needed to fight with the help of preparation and planning, not just facing something in a straight-on battle. They had met plenty of such beasts and monsters on their path so far, so Sylphie had concluded the human was one of those. He had tried to tell her off, but she had never truly believed him. But after today… she would.

They kept watching for a while longer. With every hit, the eagle had a harder time getting up. With every blow, its radiance weakened. It stumbled and failed to move its right wing. It tried to attack with the other, but the human stepped under it, and his blade became encompassed by two powerful energies—one dark, and one that powerful mana he used—as it cut upwards, severing the entire left wing.

The eagle fell to the ground, still alive but struggling. It looked up at the human with indignation, and the human just stared back.

Speaking not to it, but the three of them looking on from above, he said, "You guys come down here."

Hawkie was confused for a moment, then understood. From start to end, the human had not displayed any killing intent. He had never planned on landing a killing blow from the very beginning... because this wasn't his enemy—not truly. It was theirs.

Chapter 72

Union Oath

Jake felt it before he saw her. A new presence emerged a split second before she was fully back. A small bird appeared back on top of his head, having shifted from a sitting to a standing position.

"Welcome back, Sylphie," Jake said with a smile as he inspected the hawk.

[Sylphian Eyas – lvl 100]

Well, okay, not a hawk but an eyas, I guess. Level 100 and still a little kid, heh, Jake thought, chuckling internally.

Hawkie and Mystie also jumped over, and he ended up sitting surrounded by the two hawks as they both inspected and made bird noises at their daughter. Jake kept smiling as she happily narrated something, and both of them kept making questioning screeches. While Jake was okay-ish at speaking bird, he wasn’t fluent at all, so much of their conversation was lost on him. He could only really read intent and emotions.

Jake waited for them to finish, trying to piece together what it had been about. Luckily, he didn’t have to, as someone else clued him in.

"So, I went ahead and got your little bird pal a blessing from my fellow Primordial by making her aware of the bird’s existence, and she was very interested," Villy came in from the left side, dropping a knowledge bomb. “So yeah, the hawk has a Divine Blessing now and is a bit stronger, and will likely get a few better skills and stuff like that moving forward. The one blessing her is called Stormild and is an elemental of sorts, so do note that she may begin developing more in that direction. In case you didn’t know, she is like, half-beast, half-elemental.”

"Oh, that’s pretty cool, I guess. Is Stormild nice?" Jake asked back telepathically.

"Not at all; she is a living natural disaster. But she does like all elementals and spirits, and as your little bird is part spirit, Stormild likes her. She is an interesting little thing, that hawk, which sure also helped. So yeah, the bird will be fine."

"I see. Well, as long as this elemental thing treats Sylphie properly, it will be fine. But, do tell her to treat Sylphie nicely, okay?" He hoped this Stormild was chill like the Malefic Viper. Sylphie getting another friend would be nice.

"No worries—you might just get the chance to tell her yourself, dependent on what you choose," the Viper mysteriously answered.

Before Jake got the chance to ask, the Viper’s presence faded. It was all very mysterious for about ten seconds… before Sylphie seemed done with her conversation with her parents. He noted they were all looking at him. Mystie and Hawkie looked expectant but also a bit concerned. Jake worried about what the hell they had discussed to have those expressions, but he soon got his answer. Sylphie jumped down and landed on his lap.

She looked him in the eyes and began glowing. A magic circle coalesced in mid-air in front of her, and Jake looked at it a bit. Sylphie placed her wing on one side of the floating magic circle, and Jake quickly picked up what to do. He, too, placed his hand on the circle.

*Do you wish to begin the ritual to enter a Union Oath of Stormild with Sylphie? NOTE: Both parties can exit the ritual at any point before the final Union Oath has been made*

Jake looked at it for a bit. It was a system prompt. System prompts tended to be important. The issue was, Jake had no idea what this whole deal was about.

"Okay, Villy, get the fuck back here. What is this?"

Villy swiftly came back, almost as if he had been waiting for Jake.

"So, remember when I told you about the whole bond of equals during the whole slavery thing? Elementals and spirits, in general, are the most common users of this type of bond. Your undead pal with his Blightwraith girlfriend is an example, where he entered an equal bond with the wraith. Of course, you don’t need to do something like that; the type of bond can be very customized, especially the kind the Sylphian has. So no, not slavery. More a spirit contract. Just go ahead with the ritual for now, check out the details, and figure it out from there.”

The Viper’s words dispelled some of his doubts. For a moment there, he’d thought Sylphie was trying to bait him into a slave contract or something. Jake wasn’t entirely comfortable with the entire ordeal. He actually considered rejecting the ritual for a moment, but the big, hopeful eyes of Sylphie staring at him made him unable to.

He accepted it, and then everything kinda got weird.

Jake felt himself in two places at once. His consciousness and likely parts of his soul were dragged off somewhere along with Sylphie’s, but his body remained behind, meaning he still felt his Sphere of Perception and all that. Well, it wasn’t something he hadn’t tried before, so he just rolled with it.

In his weird soul-form, he floated through nothingness for a while until he and Sylphie both came to a stop. Jake was a bit surprised at Sylphie’s form. While Jake looked pretty much the same, except a bit more transparent, Sylphie looked like an ever-changing green creature of wind that eventually settled on her old shape.

Before the two of them was a tablet without any words besides a title at the top.

Union Oath of Stormild

Jake looked over at Sylphie, expecting her to do something. Instead, she looked back at him, looking equally perplexed.

Sylphie, this is your damn ritual, he thought. He didn’t say anything, though, letting her take her time. The reason for this was simple… Everything he saw in his sphere moved extremely slowly. Like, so slow it was almost unnoticeable. This meant time in the real world was moving at a snail’s pace during this whole ritual, so he could let her figure it out herself.

Well, it turned out she wouldn’t have to.

Two orbs of light suddenly appeared in the sky above. First, clouds spread as he heard the sound of thunder and saw flashes of lightning. Then, the entire sky appeared to catch fire as a new presence entered the weird space they were in.

It wasn’t hard for Jake to guess who it was.

"Stormild, I presume?" he asked out loud.

"That’s me."

The voice sounded like… a little girl? Not at all what he would expect from an incredibly ancient Primordial that had been around for billions, if not trillions of years. Then again, how was a being that old supposed to sound?

Also, it was interesting that she actually talked. It wasn’t some magical telepathy or anything, but just sound. What was weird, though, was how the sound appeared, or how he picked it up. Sound magic, maybe? The concept of sound? It was magic for sure.

"Ree!" Sylphie also said, flapping her wings happily.

"OOOOOHM!"

Jake heard an almost booming sound in response, and everything rattled for a moment. Yet he felt like it wasn’t an attack or anything malicious. In fact, he felt a lot of… communication? Sylphie, at least, seemed to perfectly understand that booming sound and happily responded with even more screeches and wing-flapping.

"Are you talking elemental or something?" Jake asked. He didn’t quite get what they were saying or doing, but clearly it worked for them.

"Oh, yeah,” Stormild replied. “Super much better way to talk than stupid words. Actually, words are, like, the worst way of talking. Okay, not the worst, but one of the worst. I once saw this weird fishy thing that talked by writing stuff or something. It was sooo slow and bad. Also, it only worked with water, so when all their water went poof, they couldn’t talk. Really silly, those ones. The small ones couldn’t even breathe without the water. Another silly thing. Why breathe? Never got why so many things like to do that…"

"Yeah, I agree on that one. Not having to breathe is nice." Jake nodded, ignoring how the elemental just talked about killing possibly an entire race by evaporating all the water they lived in. "Anyway, why was it we were here again? Some kind of oath or something, right? What’s it about?"

"I remembered! The ritual! Right. Just agree to serve Sylphie forever and ever and do everything she ever tells you till you die, but don’t die until she tells you, and never leave her and go wherever she wants, and stuff like that, okay?"

He needed to take a moment to absorb that rant. He was about to protest, but Sylphie was the one who began screeching madly first.

"Ree! Ree!" she huffed and puffed.

"Not like that? Oh… oh!" Stormild began changing forms.

A bird-like creature appeared before him, still nearly ten meters tall but now far smaller. Stormild looked down at him. She looked like she sniffed him a bit, and Jake felt like her presence poked his own. Maybe even his soul? It didn’t really do anything.

"It is a Bloodline!" the Primordial said, flapping her wings as thunder boomed and flames were left in their wake. "I totally get it now!" Stormild turned to Sylphie and sounded more serious than ever. “If a girl likes a boy very much—"

“No!” Jake cut in. “Just no. Seriously, what the fuck?”

Stormild looked over at Jake, almost relieved. “To be fair, I did think it was a bit weird, but I try not to judge, ya know? I never quite get you fleshies, and some have hobbies quite hard to understand. Seriously, why do you do that thing with your fleshy bits where you—"

"I think we should change the subject—now," Jake said, not leaving much up to discussion.

Sylphie just looked between them, confused and not quite getting what the conversation was about. Jake preferred to keep it that way.

The big, burning storm bird looked down at Jake. "Okay, okay. So, what do you want to do an Oath about? I still think you should just do everything Sylphie says forever."

"Yeah, not gonna happen. So how does this oath work? Some kind of contract?"

"Uhm, yeah, of course, it’s a spirit contract. Duh," Stormild said, proceeding to happily explain what the skill was about. “Didn’t big snake man tell you? You agree on stuff, and then you become bound to each other kinda. It’s a totally cool spirit thing only spirits can do; that’s why it’s called a spirit contract. My version is even better. I am the one to make sure everyone keeps their oath, because I think promises are super important. Do you know how many elementals or innocent spirits used to get screwed over? It was super unfair, so I made a better version. One where if either party breaks the oath, I fix it.”

"Fix it how?" Jake asked.

"Death."

The word was spoken with an intent that actually sent a shiver down Jake’s spine. Everything told him that this wasn’t some usual contract. Not truly. While a regular slave contract or even just other types of highly restrictive contracts would result in death if broken… Well, that was how it was meant to work. As with many other things, there were workarounds… but if a Primordial would appear to enforce an oath? Or at least part of a Primordial? That… was something. It also kind of added a subjective interpretation to the whole thing. Jake wasn’t sure about the entire thing but went with it for now.

"What are the benefits of this Union Oath?" Jake asked.

"Usually, it’s a great way to bond. Get better at fighting together. Like, ya know, just do stuff together. Also, stuff that is usually only available to one of you, as the other can be seen as a part of you. Kinda? You can even do Challenge Dungeons together sometimes. So yeah, become forever-friends."

Jake frowned. This… He really wasn’t sure about this. Jake was aware of this kind of thing. It sounded a lot like a companion bond—a type of magic he had read about some classes getting that allowed them to bind a beast. He assumed a spirit contract was the spirit version of that. It was usually a bond of equals that more or less made them codependent. Many skills and types of magic would be unlocked, and a permanent bond would be formed. It was a lifelong partnership where they would spend their entire lives never away from each other… and Jake didn’t want that.

Not to be misunderstood, he liked Sylphie. But he also liked being alone. He was a lone hunter, and he knew that. That didn’t mean he could never work with others—he had a great time hunting with Hawkie—but he wasn’t going to make a lifelong commitment to always hunt as a pair with Sylphie. It wasn’t fair to either him or Sylphie. It would limit both their freedoms, which made it out of the question.

He looked over at Sylphie. "Is this really something you want? I am not saying we can’t be forever-friends, but do we need to swear to each other we will? It will mean we will have to always be together. You will have to sit and wait while I do alchemy… Do you really want that?"

Sylphie had seemed okay with everything until now, yet her eyes opened wide when he mentioned that. He knew she wasn’t a fan of him always sitting on his ass, crafting, and often tried to make him do stuff, so when she imagined having to wait for him… her distress was obvious.

"Ree!" Sylphie said as she flapped her wings in panic at Stormild.

"Wait, why would you need to do that?" Stormild asked, looking genuinely confused. "That sounds like a silly rule to have. Why include that? Seems super silly. Just be friends, and all is okay and promise each other stuff and make the oath. Then Sylphie can enter the Treasure Hunt, and I get stuff just like big snake man."

She seemed very pushy, as she even poked Sylphie with her ethereal wing. “You want to enter the Treasure Hunt with Uncle, right? I am sure you can find tasty stuff in there. Also, you will be able to do more fun stuff with Uncle in the future if you want to. You want that, right?”

Sylphie did want that.

And Jake? Jake considered if this was really a thing one could just exploit.

"So, you mean to tell me we can just create this Union Oath, live our lives entirely independent of each other, but still have some benefits, like allowing Sylphie to enter the Treasure Hunt with me? " Jake asked clarifyingly. “I assume this bond can even be harnessed to communicate and things like that? A bit like a blessing from a god? Any drawback if either party gets hurt—or worse, dies?"

"Sure, you can think of it a bit like a blessing. It’s kinda wrong, but you can. And sure, you can just get all the good stuff and not the bad stuff. Well, you won’t benefit as much as those who make a big Union Oath, but you will still get some of the good stuff. Also, it will be super sad if either of you dies, right? But nah, you don’t need to include a rule about both parties dying if the other does. Many do, though. Dunno why."

"What will this Union Oath need to include, specifically?"

"A promise. You know, an Oath? The Spirit Contract needs that to work.”

"Alright, Villy, quick thoughts before I do something dumb?" Jake quickly threw towards the Viper.

"This is what I planned. It’s a good thing. Stormild’s contract is a bit.. exploitative. Towards the system and its rules, that is. It is the best kind there is, besides maybe some of the stuff Eversmile cooks up. To you, the benefits will be borderline nonexistent with no real drawbacks at all, but it will help the hawk a lot. Be aware that you can only have one such contract active at a time, though." Villy’s prompt answer dispelled much of Jake’s doubt. He knew all of this had been partly orchestrated by the Viper… but not entirely.

He had a feeling Stormild wasn’t easily manipulated. She seemed simple and childish, but his instincts told him everything she did was done with purpose and deliberation. Stormild most certainly was childish and had a very naïve outlook on some things for sure, but that didn’t mean she couldn’t comprehend the intents of others. He was pretty sure she’d known what this was all about from the beginning, and was now having fun with them. The comments and jokes were just her enjoying the company. At least, he got the impression she was enjoying herself in their company.

"Well, let’s get to it then. If you want to, Sylphie?" Jake asked the small hawk.

She happily screeched and flew over to Jake, nuzzling up to him. He wasn’t certain of all the impacts this Union Oath would have, but he had a feeling it wasn’t something he would come to regret.

Chapter 73

A Higher Power? No Thanks

Jake had signed quite a few contracts during his life. It had been a staple of his pre-system work, and of course, when you made large and important purchases such as a car or a home, you had to sign. So he knew a bit about signing stuff, and there were a few things one always had to remember.

First and foremost was, naturally, to spend an unreasonable amount of time practicing your signature… solely not to be embarrassed when you signed like a kid during an important business meeting, or when the judgemental lady from the bank stared over your shoulder. All of this while being fully aware that having a good-looking signature was just a stupid social construct created by archaic and unreasonable expectations in a world where digitalization had taken over… so why even bother improving your handwriting?

Anyway, the second thing one had to remember was to always read the contract closely. Jake’s mom had always told a horror story of how her father’s brother’s best friend’s sister’s husband once signed without reading the contract, and had ended up buying the wrong car. In retrospect, it was a bad story, but she had told it to him so many times.

The rule of reading contracts had only become more important after the system came. At least, in some ways. In others, not so much. Because each contract now gave one a sense of what they were about. You couldn’t sign it unless the system believed you understood it. But, of course, there were levels to understanding. For example, one could fail to consider the future properly but think the contract was worth it in the short term. So one had to always consider a contract properly before signing and take some time to go over it in one’s head. If possible, that meant waiting to sign till the next day to sleep on it.

Now, this wasn’t a possibility when floating in some weird soul-space-thing with a half-elemental, half-beast hawk and an ancient living natural disaster. But then again, the contract wasn’t exactly complicated. The massive tablet only had a few words on it, though they were quite open to interpretation.

Awesomest Uncle Jake Thayne and Bestest Bird Sylphie agree to be Forever-Friends.

"Is this seriously enough?" Jake asked, highly skeptical of the entire thing.

"Seems fine to me?" Stormild answered, looking at him like he was stupid.

"Ree!" Sylphie agreed. She had been the one behind the wording of the contract.

"Seriously?" Jake reiterated.

"Yep."

"So, hypothetically speaking, what would breaking this contract look like? What if Sylphie and I have a disagreement? Or maybe we just don’t meet and talk for a while? Does that mean that one day it suddenly counts as us breaking it? Also, what if either of us dies? Doesn’t that automatically mean the other party broke the terms?"

Every fiber of his being refused to believe this could count as a proper contract. Perhaps it was his years in the corporate world, but this couldn’t be okay, could it?

"Uhm, friends sometimes fight, so no problems there. I am still super good friends with big snake man, and we didn’t meet in super-duper long, so that’s fine too, I guess? Oh! And you can be friends with dead people too. My last best friend—er, Chosen—died because she couldn’t figure out how to become a god, but we’re still friends.” Stormild’s answer completely dispelled all of Jake’s concerns.

“Ree! Ree!” Sylphie agreed, adding on something more.

“Right on, Sylphie!" Stormild said as she flew around them in a circle, clearly in a great mood. “Dad is still Dad if Dad dies, and Uncle is still Uncle even if Uncle dies, so why is Forever-Friend not still Forever-Friend even after death? Friendships can have all shapes and sizes, so as long as you don’t outright say you aren’t Forever-Friends anymore, all is good. Oh! And you have to mean it. Sometimes people say stuff they don’t mean in anger, right?”

"Ree?" Sylphie asked.

"Of course we’re friends!" Stormild replied.

"Ree?" Sylphie then asked, looking at Jake.

"Well, big snake man is my friend, and Uncle is a friend of big snake man, so we’re also friends,” Stormild explained. “Oh, hey! It’s not often I’m hanging out with two friends like this! People normally act all weird and beg me not to kill them and stuff. Some even do beg me to kill them, which is even weirder? Oh, do you know the Primordial Church? They are super weird, those ones.”

"Ree! Ree?"

"For sure! This one time I…"

Jake just stood there and zoned out as the Primordial began telling her story. This one time, she’d been getting chased by fanatics that tried to find the planets she would pass by next to hopefully be consumed by her. To her credit, she apparently tried to actively avoid planets with life on them… unless they were "super-much in the way," that is. Eventually, she went into another totally unrelated story.

He had a lot to consider with this contract, if you could even call it that. Jake knew it was pretty much just an excuse to allow Sylphie to enter things like the Treasure Hunt, and to give her some valuable Records. It was one-sided for sure, but Jake was okay with that. It didn’t seem like this would impede him in any way, but instead help Sylphie in the long run.

Considering the Viper clearly wanted Jake to become a god, and the Viper approved of this, he reckoned it would all end fine. He also knew that Villy had become aware of the tablet’s contents and hadn’t commented on it, giving his subtle approval.

"… and then he did a backflip, snapped the bad guy’s neck, and saved the day!" Stormild finished, Sylphie flapping her wings in excitement and wanting the Primordial to tell another story.

Sadly, Jake was a party-pooper and brought the two distracted birds back to what was important.

"How do we go about making the Union Oath?" Jake asked, bringing attention back to him.

"Oh, yeah, let’s get that done!" Stormild agreed as the tablet lit up.

The words on the tablet began glowing with different colors as two imprints appeared on the tablet. A larger imprint sat on top of it all, looking almost like a thundercloud ready to judge the ones making the Oath.

“Just touch the tablet with something and make the Oath!” the Primordial explained. “Then, the system will ask, and you just accept, and all is good, and you’ll be Forever-Friends!"

Sylphie didn’t hesitate to fly over and touch the imprint with her wing. Jake followed suit soon after and placed his hand on it. The moment he did so, he felt something. He felt like a tendril extended from the tablet and into him… Into his soul.

It worked its way all the way into the innermost layer as a connection was established. He intimately felt that two other connections were also extended—one towards Sylphie and the other towards Stormild. It was a contract with three parties: himself and Sylphie as the subjects, and Stormild the facilitator and higher power ordaining it.

Jake felt the system probe until it asked for his consent in the contract. He felt as though his mind downloaded an understanding of it… and it truly was a vague contract. It could only be so vague because it wasn’t actually the system itself that enforced it, but Stormild herself. He and Sylphie were equal in the contract… but Stormild was above him. Able to judge him. Decide if he broke it. Hold power over him. Control him.

THUMP!

A pulse went through the connection. Jake realized this contract required him to acknowledge something he didn’t like to. Superiority. Not just in Strength but status. Existence. For him to recognize Stormild as an entity that was like an unreachable heaven that could bring down a tribulation upon him if he went against her will. It required him to allow her will to trump his own.

THUMP!

He didn’t like that.

He didn’t like that at all.

But more than anything… his Bloodline—his base of existence—would never allow it.

THUMP!

The entire space around them began shaking. Sylphie only looked a bit confused, while Jake had no idea what Stormild was thinking. He didn’t particularly care to take note, either, as he felt a sense of indignation boil up. Had he misunderstood the contract? Partly… but not really. At that final moment, he realized that he couldn’t accept another entity to be recognized as a superior existence.

But the thing was, he still wanted the contract. The Union Oath hadn’t stopped.

THUMP!

Another pulse was sent into the tablet. Jake’s symbol shook as a crack formed.

THUMP!

The crack expanded across the tablet, not seeking to destroy it… but equalize it. The heaven above—the symbolization of Stormild—was cracked too.

THUMP!

Jake felt the entire base of the skill and magic fight against him. He was breaking rules right now, seeking to supersede the intended function of the contract. His will and Bloodline managed to bend the contract—the tablet responded, and the stated words began changing.

Yet just as the shift began, Jake felt an immense wave of weakness, and his sense of danger exploded. He was trying to mess with levels of magic and power he couldn’t even begin to touch upon. While he had the qualitative ability to cause change… he didn’t have the quantity. He was simply too weak. Perhaps he would survive, but he would drain his own soul of energy, possibly causing harm to anything but the most vital of functions.

He simply wasn’t powerful enough to do it with his own power.

But he knew someone who was.

Jake felt the ever-present connection and began tugging on it. He needed power. He needed quantity. So he got some. Normally, it was a connection one could only send requests through, using it to ask for power that could then be given with consent from the god. But Jake? Jake was a heretic. He didn’t need to ask permission.

Vilastromoz smiled as he felt the pull from beyond the void, more a demand than a request. One he initially failed to resist, as the one trying to pull on his power simply didn’t need to ask—which was great, because this was an instance where he couldn’t assist under normal circumstances. Jake had reached a stage where he didn’t need to ask, just take. Vilastromos knew it was due to the profession, which was very much based on his Bloodline, that unreasonable thing. Did this mean the Viper couldn’t stop it? No, it didn’t. But that wasn’t something he was going to do, as this was exactly what he wanted.

He had a plan. As the Viper opened the floodgates and allowed his Chosen to pull all he needed, he cracked a grin. His gamble had paid off; he felt the information about the contract flood his mind as he established a connection with the tablet, and thus the skill in question.

"I—no, we—win this one."

A final pulse was sent into the tablet. All pulses prior had only caused minor cracks and suppressed what was happening on the tablet, but this one? This one had the power to cause change.

Out of the symbol depicting Jake came a green, slithering figure that reached towards the heavens, flew up, and coiled around it. Then everything was pulled down to the level of Sylphie and Jake, the snake remaining coiled around the cloud and suppressing it.

Cracked, shadowy lines of dark green energy pulsated on the entire tablet, giving off the aura of the Viper—except for Jake’s own symbol, which kept glowing an almost reddish color. The entire tablet looked half-destroyed already.

Jake felt his heartbeat slow down as he became fully aware: The nature of the contract had been changed. He looked over at Sylphie as he felt a change. Just at that moment, Sylphie completely froze as if time stopped, while Jake remained unaffected.

"I knew you were interesting," he heard a new voice say. No, Stormild? It sounded slightly older than before… Still like a teenager, though.

"Vilastromoz and his silly games," Stormild continued as she looked down at him. "What an utter display of unnecessary control and such a contrived way to achieve his means. Doesn’t seem like all of this was your plan from the start. A gamble on the Viper’s part? This would regularly not be possible. Ah, the Bloodline? Does it allow you to show absolute disregard for any suppression? Innate defiance and the inability to be in the position of an inferior? Quite a few drawbacks too with that one, I would reckon, but it explains a lot. Of course, that’s not the only thing it does either, is it? You become more and more interesting by the second."

Jake looked up at her, meeting her gaze. He felt her intent press down on him unrestrained. It was the kind of pressure that would knock out many weaker gods, but Jake stood unaffected. "I just came here for a contract between Sylphie and me; I wasn’t aware it included being your little servant."

"It does not; you merely interpreted it as such because it was a possibility innate to the contract. For any Union Oath, there needs to be a higher power to facilitate it, or it becomes unstable. You have broken the basic foundation of the contract like this, and it will not last more than a few decades at most, with nothing able to break it till then, making the contents of the Oath itself meaningless. Was this your plan all along? If so, kudos to you; I didn’t see that one coming. I could ask how you did it and how you discovered a new loophole, but I won’t. That would be no fun, now, would it?” Stormild didn’t seem at all angry, but more amused.

"As I said, I just wanted to help Sylphie along. What would the Viper even get out of this besides helping me?"

"Ah, you truly don’t know? Well, I reckon you will hear both sides, but what he just did was insert himself in the foundation of the skill. I would guess he is studying it and trying to learn something, or possibly even steal a few concepts. A rude gesture to further his own power, or perhaps he was simply overprotective of his Chosen? Likely both. Either way, what’s done is done, and I will get my payment later. You can help make up for it by treating this interesting creature well and making sure she realizes her full potential." The Primordial’s everchanging form swirled around the hawk.

"Of course I will," Jake said.

That wasn’t even a question. He scratched his chin, actually feeling a bit bad now that he knew everything being a bit fucked was his own fault. He did know that Stormild would be the one in charge of the contract… but when it came down to it, to the direct feeling of being made a subject subservient to it, he’d innately just resisted. Without the Viper’s power, he would have had to break off the contract or end up severely injuring himself in a struggle he couldn’t possibly win. Not that any of it mattered now. The contract could no longer be broken as, well, there was no one to judge if it was broken.

"Anyway, I’m sorry things got a bit messy. I hope you’ll continue to be nice to Sylphie," Jake said in the end.

He could put a bit of his pride aside and apologize if it meant Sylphie being treated better. Besides, it was his fault, so… yeah. Anyway, contract successfully made, kinda—though from his understanding, it was now one no one could break, but one that would instead naturally disappear within a few decades, with no one really holding any control over it. Honestly? A pure win in his mind. It was quite lucky this innate defiance hadn’t been a thing before the system.... If it had been, getting a car loan would have been very awkward.

“No worries," she answered nonchalantly. “Today has been very eventful and not one I regret. On the contrary, it has been quite interesting and included some new experiences. A rarity, I must tell you.”

"Final thing… Quite the personality change, isn’t it?"

"Wind, lightning, and fire are never stable forms. The storm is never static. It bends as it meets a mountain and ascends when it encounters an updraft. Likewise, I change. Sometimes a situation calls for another state of mind, and this one was one such case. A case that has now been concluded. The Union Oath is technically made, the connection created, and the contract established. With that, I see no need to keep you here any longer, as I believe you have overstayed your welcome. Ah, but I shall keep the hawk here a bit longer. Till next we meet, Jake Thayne, Chosen of the Malefic Viper and Uncle of Sylphie."

With those words, Jake felt himself being forcefully ejected. He woke up in the real world a split second later with a shock. He nearly fell backwards, only able to stabilize himself, as he had his sphere still there and active. Sylphie nearly fell off his head too, but luckily he was quick to make sure she didn’t.

"Goodbye to you too," he muttered, a bit miffed—not only at being forcefully ejected, but at being forced to now explain what the hell had happened to the two anxious parent-hawks while their daughter was still unresponsive.

Honestly, it has been a bizarre day, Jake thought as he began explaining stuff to the hawks.

Chapter 74

Scorching the Plains

Trying to explain to two anxious hawks that their daughter was just relaxing with a Primordial that also happened to be a living natural disaster wasn’t the easiest. They seemed more than a bit worried, but Jake kept assuring them it would all be fine. It did help that Sylphie was still on top of his head, looking to be asleep.

Anyway, the two of them got the gist of it quite quickly and overall seemed to approve of the entire situation, even if it wasn’t optimal. They did get that Jake and Sylphie had now "solidified" their relationship, which appeared to be the most important aspect to them. In the end, they waited in silence for Sylphie to also wake up.

Jake himself had a few other things he had to go through during this wait, so the silence was welcome. One of which was a notification—or rather, notifications. Ones he had gotten during his time in the space with Stormild, but hadn’t yet checked, as he knew what they were about. They were the most random levels Jake could remember ever getting.

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 124 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 125 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 127 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Two levels for… nothing? Or perhaps something. He decided to send a quick one towards Villy to get an explanation.

"So, what was all that stuff about? And why did I get two profession levels for it?" Jake asked his Patron Primordial.

Villy responded promptly, having no doubt expected Jake to demand an explanation. "I just gambled with your life to get a few personal benefits without telling you beforehand. Alright, in all seriousness, I expected the response you had there. Why do you ask? Because do you have any idea how hard it was to even give you a blessing? One that wasn’t even conditional in any way, but a pure benefit? You don’t even seem to be aware of how damn annoying it was in the first many months. I felt constant aggression through the connection. That has disappeared now after your evolution. So yeah, I put two and two together and reckoned your Bloodline—and thus you—hated ever being put in a position where you have to recognize another existence as superior. The rest of it was just exploitation of a loophole in Stormild’s skill by using our peculiar bond and the opening your Bloodline made. And the levels? Well, because you did something very heretic-chosen of you.”

"And what do you get out of it?" Jake asked, accepting the rest of the explanation. Those things kinda made sense, right?

But the Viper didn’t disclose what skin he had in the game. “Knowledge. Stormild has insights into soul magic I do not, and I wanted to find inspiration through her skill. I couldn’t tell you about it beforehand, because you couldn’t have accepted the contract if you’d known. You would have done so partly with the intent of breaking it from the start. As I said, it was a gamble. Honestly, what I get out of it has little relevance to you. I would have told you if it was possible, but then you wouldn’t have gotten those levels or made the contract, so everything turned out fine, right?"

Jake could hear in the Viper’s voice that he was actually trying to justify it. It was a weird kind of apology, but Jake understood. Apologizing wasn’t something he liked doing either, but sometimes something was just your fault, and it was better to apologize. He also perfectly understood the Viper not wanting Jake to harbor some hidden resentment or anything like that. Hence, he dispelled that right away.

"Well yeah, I guess stuff turned out fine,” Jake answered with a smile, getting a weird look from Hawkie and Mystie. “I reckon you knew Stormild enough to predict her reaction, even if she does seem a bit eccentric. Just give me a heads-up when you can, and if nothing else, I’ll be sure to get some petty revenge, alright?"

"Sure thing, mate. See you around and take care," the Primordial said, sounding a bit relieved.

"You too," Jake answered out loud, still smiling. More weird looks from the hawks. Jake just ignored it, staying silent and waiting for the smallest of the hawks—the one sitting on his head—to awaken.

Five minutes later, Sylphie woke up. Her awakening wasn’t as dramatic as Jake nearly falling off his chair, but she just opened her eyes, made a cute yawning sound, and oriented herself. However, she did not appear to have any intentions of getting up. She shook herself a bit back and forth to sit more snuggly on top of his head.

"So, did you and Stormild have a nice talk?" he asked.

Sylphie made a small screech of confirmation before she began a bird-charade of everything they had talked about. Jake naturally didn’t get half of it, but her parents were sure interested.

Jake began instead inspecting what this whole Union Oath ritual had all been about. He could vaguely feel a connection to Sylphie, but only when he really focused. It wasn’t like anything he had quite experienced before, and the connection felt far weaker than the one he had with the Viper. Jake had assumed this one would be stronger, but it evidently wasn’t.

He did feel a certain quality to it. Like he couldn’t break it no matter what, which was the same as what his bond to Villy had changed into after his last evolution. The connection was naturally of the weird metaphysical sort, so it did make him wonder if he could use it to communicate with Sylphie across vast distances or something.

It did make him consider one thing, though. One he probably should have a long time ago. The thought that he could now feel if Sylphie was in danger popped into his head… but he’d already been able to do that before. That was how he’d managed to come and stop the Prima in time. Was it just pure intuition from his Bloodline? Had they already had some hidden connection? He had no idea, and quite frankly, it wasn’t something he cared much to explore. It was there; it was good. Ultimately, the whole bond was worth it just for Sylphie’s ability to enter the Treasure Hunt and likely also get some Records and stuff from Jake. Apropos the Treasure Hunt…

"Sylphie," Jake said, getting her attention. She stopped chatting with her parents. "The Treasure Hunt is in a bit under two weeks. I give you thirteen days. Thirteen days, and if you aren’t level 110 by that time, you aren’t coming along to the Treasure Hunt. Oh, and if you get in trouble and need help again—which I will know about, or Stormild will tell me—you also won’t come. This is all for your own safety, so do I make myself clear?"

Sometimes a bit of tough love was necessary. Jake wanted to take Sylphie along, but he didn’t want to unnecessarily take any risks or hamper his own abilities during the hunt. They would very likely be splitting up or something for a lot of the time, so she needed to take care of herself and also get used to her new strength as a D-grade. She was green in all ways when it came to fighting—and in color—and she needed to be able to stand on her own feet, even if she was young.

Mystie was the first to answer. She made a screech and motioned for them to leave. Jake shut that down right away.

"No, this is Sylphie. Unfortunately, you and Hawkie can’t come along to the Treasure Hunt, and she will need to learn to fight alone. It will only hurt her in the future if she gets too used to having her parents as support and builds her fighting style around that, so this time Sylphie has to go alone.”

Mystie answered with an angry screech, but Hawkie came in and calmed her down, agreeing with Jake. Jake threw his old bird-pal a nod. While he felt like Hawkie didn’t like it, the hawk at least understood that what Jake said was the truth.

As for Sylphie?

"Ree!"

She screeched with determination as she got up halfway through her mom’s protest. All the focus turned to her as she made a few more screeches, making her mom back down and her dad look incredibly proud. Jake didn’t need to speak hawk to get the gist of it. She, too, approved of his message, even if he could feel her feet shake a bit atop his noggin, as she was obviously a bit nervous. She had never really been hunting enemies around her level or above alone before. She had killed D-grades solo before level 100… but none had truly been able to challenge her.

Without wasting any time, she jumped down on Jake’s shoulder, rubbed her head against his cheek, and took flight. Her parents stared after her for a moment and made a screech at one another before they also took off—in a slightly different direction than Sylphie. They clearly didn’t want to be too outdone by her, even if they couldn’t join the Treasure Hunt.

Jake was also proud of her. He did guess Stormild had also said something, but that didn’t have any impact on his pride.

Go get them, Sylphie.

He himself didn’t pull out his cauldron. No, instead, he took out his bow. It was the new bow he had gotten from Sultan—the one that, during the fight with the Eagle Prima, had proven to be more of a liability than anything else. Looking at it in his hand, he Identified it once more.

[Embered Bow of Scorching Plains (Epic)] – A bow made from an unknown type of wood that has been soaked in potent fire-affinity mana for a long period of time without being burned and then infused with a dozen other valuable materials. All brought to life by an incredibly talented bowyer. The bow’s structure is resilient yet flexible, the string near unbreakable for anyone below C-grade. The two gemstones passively absorb and transform mana into that of the fire affinity, imbuing all arrows fired by this bow with fire mana and the concept of embers. The two gemstones can be emptied of energy to release a large burst of fire-affinity mana in the form of a giant arrow that explodes on impact, scorching the plains below. Enchantments: Ember Arrows. Scorching Plains.

Requirements: Lvl 105+ in any humanoid race.

Jake instantly spotted the issue right away in the description. It had a passive function to imbue every single arrow fired with a bit of fire energy, making them, in theory, more effective. This would make all normal arrows deal a bit of extra fire damage and make arrows already of the fire affinity even more powerful, which made sense if that bowyer Maria was an archer focusing on fire magic herself.

The issue was, Jake didn’t shoot regular arrows but arcane arrows. Heck, the only reason his arrows played well with his poison was that it was his poison and not someone else’s. The fire mana, in this case, was without intent and should hypothetically not mess with anything, but Jake’s arcane affinity was a bit iffy to work with—especially his more destructive variant.

With his destructive variant, the fire mana would just fight the arcane mana and end up being destroyed, expending a bit of arcane mana and resulting in a net negative. The stable version was better in that it completely rejected the fire mana. All this did was make the fire mana disperse into the atmosphere and not have any effect.

The final part of the bow was the Scorched Plains enchant. He hadn’t tested that one yet.

So he went to do that. Jake naturally planned on transmuting the bow, but he wanted to get a bit more familiar with it before doing that. He already had an approach in mind, and his understanding of the bow was naturally one of the primary factors for how effective a transmutation he could make.

Jake took flight, heading out of Haven and onto the empty plains. He made sure not to go where people traveled to and from the Fort, but a good distance away from any civilization. He ended up going to the area where the Minotaur Mindchief had once been, thinking that the old barn would be a nice thing to test it on. He also wouldn’t feel bad about burning that shithole down.

When he got there, he noticed only a few beasts in the area. Most of the cows were just chilling, doing nothing. Seeing no reason to roast any beef, Jake activated his Pride of the Malefic Viper and infused his presence for a loud yell.

"FIRE DRILL!"

His voice was even infused with his Willpower, echoing far and wide. That quickly got all the bovines’ attention, and they began mooing and fleeing from the area. He did feel a bit bad about scaring the rather harmless cows, but it was better to scare than kill them.

He took out his bow and started doing some simple tests. Then, using his old uncommon-rarity quiver, he drew an arrow and fired it. As he drew the string, he felt fire mana being infused into the arrow. The arrowhead began glowing, and the wood had fiery red lines running through it. When he released the string, the arrow flew forth and broke apart when it hit the ground, sending the fire mana into the soil.

Actually quite decent, Jake thought. Far less powerful than his arcane arrows, but not bad at all. He especially liked that the arrow didn’t just explode, but sent the fire mana into the target it hit—which was excellent attention to detail.

Jake kept practicing for a few more hours, just using the uncommon-rarity arrows. He inspected how the mana moved and how the two gemstones collected atmospheric mana and transformed it into fire mana—all of it with the sole intent of transforming it into an arcane variant. Jake didn’t want to lose the ability to infuse the arrows with more mana, just making it all arcane mana instead.

By that time, the entire area around him was devoid of life, and he decided it was a good time to use the ultimate move of the bow.

He didn’t need to be told what to do; the item allowed him to instinctively know. Jake positioned himself on a platform of mana as he began. Raising the bow, his intent became clear, and it responded.

The entire body of the bow caught fire, and the two gems on each end began glowing. Jake drew the now red-glowing string as mana gathered from the gemstones. A long, almost spear-shaped arrow appeared on the string, more than three meters in length. It was even bigger than nearly all of his arrows from Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, if not all of them.

Both gems stopped glowing almost instantly. The arrow hadn’t even taken a second to condense.

Letting go of the string, a torrent of flames was released as the arrow descended, surrounded by an inferno. When it hit the ground, it didn’t explode. At least, not in the way he’d expected from the bow’s description.

Instead, it sent out an almost entirely horizontal pulse of flames that, quite literally, scorched across the plains. The fire hugged the ground, almost like liquid moving across the landscape, burning the ground in its path and leaving only ashes behind.

Fire snaked up the barn’s sides, reducing the whole building to rubble.

In but a few moments, the entire landscape more than five kilometers in diameter was reduced to a huge, circular burn mark. Not a single building remained, and everything had been flattened. The power of the strike would have likely killed most beings below D-grade before they even got a chance to respond. It also would’ve injured many, if not most, low-grade D-grades quite badly.

"Yeah, I can work with this," Jake said as he smiled. He had a feeling the transmutation would turn out just fine.

Chapter 75

Bow & Blade

Jake had wanted to get transmuting right after he regenerated his resources, but found that the bow looked a bit… sluggish? It was no longer glowing, and the gems also looked completely inert. He came to realize he would need to give the poor bow a break before he began changing stuff. So he put it in his spatial storage and found that it could luckily still restore its mana within there.

He considered what to do, and with his proximity to the Fort, he decided to check there first to see if Arnold was done tinkering with his Nanoblade.

The trip there was swift, as he used One Step Mile to cross the plains. Of course, it wasn’t as fast as when he’d gone to save the hawks, but it was still a nice, casual speed faster than the fastest fighter jet of old Earth.

Once more, the Fort had expanded. He saw that more buildings had popped up in the brief time he was not there, but the biggest change had happened at the central Fort. The courtyard was no longer used as a big smithy, but was instead nearly devoid of anything besides a few larger ongoing construction projects.

Jake frowned, wondering what they were up to, but reckoned he could just ask Arnold. He did see that all the blacksmiths who used to work there had gotten their own little district. Well, they would have had to move eventually anyway due to limited space.

He flew directly down and landed in the courtyard, inspecting the construction more closely. It looked like the beginnings of some kind of assembly line. Was Arnold planning on mass-producing stuff? That would be kind of insane.

Entering the citadel building itself, he spotted Arnold in his lab. The man was hunched over a table, looking through some kind of microscope at a thin piece of some material that looked like glass. Jake entered the room without the man even noticing and snuck up behind him. He wondered why all the drones flying above didn’t react despite clearly noticing him.

Jake leaned over Arnold’s shoulder and looked down at the piece of glass. He focused and saw that many microscopic patterns had been etched into it, almost looking like veins. Maybe ley-lines? All the lines were straight and very angular, looking very sci-fi. It was some insanely precise work, and each was so small even he had issues seeing it.

"That’s some advanced stuff. Is that shard from the golem?" Jake finally asked after looking for a while.

A part of him had hoped for Arnold to get surprised, but the man just casually answered, "Yes, this particular piece is from beneath the third layer of the metal, functioning almost like a circuit board."

Well, he is no fun, Jake joked with himself. "Yeah, those vein-like things are damn small. As I said, very advanced. But I came to ask if—"

Arnold interrupted him by jerking back and looking at Jake with bloodshot eyes. "What veins!? Can you see them!?"

"Well, yeah?"

"How?" the man asked, looking genuinely confused.

"Because Perception is the best stat. Duh," Jake answered again, totally serious.

"I am aware of its importance, and I already possess over 1700 in it. I cannot see how that could be the—"

"Casual," Jake said, waving him off. "Who doesn’t have at least five of the big ones already?" Well, he was nearly at 6000 Perception himself, actually, but no need to brag, right?

He was a bit surprised that the man had 1700 in Perception, though. That was pretty good, honestly. Granted, Jake’s lowest stat was 2025 in Strength, but he also knew he was a bit of a cheat, after all. Without percentage amplifiers or items, Jake only had 1190, and he even got quite a few points from his class. This meant Arnold had actually put points in Perception or at least had Perception-based gear, and his class and/or profession likely gave Perception too. Well, his high level sure also contributed.

[Human – lvl 117]

"Can you… can you describe them?" Arnold asked after looking a bit confused. "I have been working on a microscope to allow me to view them better, but they simply don’t work as they should. The amplification distorts the patterns and interferes with the interpretation, and I need to use a vastly inferior version than before the system…"

Jake frowned for a bit but soon nodded. "Sure, but can you let me get a look-see down that microscope first?"

"Go ahead!" Arnold said, stepping back.

Jake took a look down the microscope, and… holy shit, it sucked. Like, sure, it amplified things a bit, but compared to him just squinting a bit, it was nothing. It was likely it blurred everything. Had the system nerfed observation tools?

"Do all microscopes suck like this?" Jake asked quite curtly.

"Yes, sadly. No amount of mirrors or any conventional concepts of making microscopes or even binoculars work properly anymore. I can make some tools that help a bit, but in many cases, looking with your bare eyes provides the clearest image…" Arnold’s voice was heavy with resignation. "Now, please describe the patterns!"

"Fine," Jake relented as he opened the palm of his hand and focused.

His presence blanketed the laboratory, making Arnold take a step back, but the man didn’t show any other reaction than that. The reason Jake did this was that, honestly… it was easier to show than to tell.

Strings sprang from his hand as he weaved an image. Jake took it as a learning opportunity to properly copy what he had seen. He even sent out a string to pick up the shard, holding it up before him with the hand he didn’t use to summon strings.

Arnold just stood silently, dazzled by the display for a few moments, then quickly summoned what looked like a tablet and pointed it at the ongoing construction of mana strings. Jake felt that his mana was being scanned but naturally didn’t fight. He had nothing to lose by Arnold figuring all this stuff out and pushing him forward a bit.

Jake pretty much saw all this as investing in the future. Arnold seemed like a straightforward kind of dude, so Jake wasn’t scared of him suddenly running off when some other large city came and offered him a big new lab and stuff like that. Besides, if he did, Jake would just have to travel a bit further to get his stuff and make sure to get his due. Arnold owed Jake, and he knew it.

It took around half an hour to finish weaving his tapestry and for Arnold to properly record it all. By that time, Jake thought it was time to ask about what he’d come for.

"So, is the Nanoblade done?"

Arnold looked confused for a second before he remembered. "Right! It has been done for over a week; it should be just over here…"

He shuffled to one of the many shelves and took a large case down. Arnold began explaining as he carried it over. "Using some of my newest aluabsorbant composite materials, I have coated the blade with this to actually give it proper mana conductivity and make the blade more powerful in every way. I attempted to attune it to your unique form of mana, but it was not feasible. However, I did manage to heighten the mana conductivity of the blade further, and a rarity upgrade was achieved."

The man opened up the case on a table in front of Jake, showing the sword. It looked nearly exactly the same as before, except the blade now had a silver sheen to it. The handle also looked like it had a do-over, and overall, the entire blade looked damn sleek. Jake Identified it and was quite pleased.

[Aluabsorbant Nanoblade Sword (Rare)] – The blade is an ultrathin Nanoblade made out of Carbon Fiber, making it both incredibly durable and sharp. It has also been coated with a thin layer of unattuned Aluabsorbant. The blade itself can cut most materials effortlessly but has little to no effectiveness against magical wards or defenses. The coating on the blade allows it to have an incredibly high level of mana conductivity and can handle most types of mana. The handle makes all mana infused into this weapon more potent. Enchantments: Extreme Conductivity. Intermediate Mana Amplification.

Requirements: Lvl 110+ in any humanoid race.

"Looking good," Jake said before asking, "Have you managed to apply any knowledge you gained from the golem?"

"… I am still trying to figure out exactly what kind of metal composite the exterior is made of, and have begun preliminary examinations of the eyes of the golem and some of the more easily accessible components.”

In other words, the dude had a long time to go before any tangible progress would happen.

"Well, in that case, do you have anything else to give me, or something you need help with?" Jake asked. The last part was mainly to be polite.

"I do not believe I have any other items that would be of interest to you, but I have extracted a hundred and thirty-five more shards so far and could use your help mapping out the—"

"Anyway, nice talking to you again. Gotta go!"

Jake ran like the wind. As he went for the roof, he saw Arnold stand back in his lab, not reacting for a few seconds. The madman eventually just shrugged and returned to tinkering with stuff.

Shaking his head, Jake took flight and headed back towards Haven again. He landed just outside the Fort and used One Step Mile to cross the plains until he reached the forest, which he just flew over back to his valley.

Jake did a quick check of his underground lab that was still under construction. Hank was really going all-out and working on making it closer to an entire underground complex. Several large rooms had been added, and he really made use of the fact that he could build in nearly unlimited ways with how much space there was—and the fact that magic was a thing.

He doubted it would even be ready for the Treasure Hunt, but it wasn’t like he was actually in a rush. For now, he was still focused on elixirs—which he didn’t need a secure lab to make—so he went back to his porch as always and took out his cauldron.

It was only while waiting for the bow to recharge before the transmutation, of course.

Jake took out the bow too and laid it on the ground as he began brewing. He felt like it recharged a bit faster while in the sun. Or maybe he was just imagining it. But honestly, it could just be the Pylon making it so that it got recharged faster, and he wasn’t curious enough to truly find out.

He ended up making six more Perception-increasing elixirs, all of which he consumed right there and then, getting another +18 Perception—because one could never have too much Perception.

The reason he stopped crafting was that the bow was ready. He chugged down a mana potion as he got to work. A plan had already formed in his mind during all his practice, and it was actually straightforward.

Fire affinity bad, arcane affinity good. Ember Arrows bad, Arcane Hunter’s Arrows good. His goal would be to take everything that was fire-focused and make it arcane-focused. He even planned on specifically transmuting the arrow part to work with his own skill. Jake had a very strong suspicion that Ember Arrows was a skill the creator herself had, and that was how she had added it.

Jake thought he could transmute that to his own Arcane Hunter’s Arrows. Limiting it to only work with that one skill would take less energy, and as far as he could tell, the Scorched Plains attack was bound to the Ember Arrow skill.

He had also noticed something else interesting. The fire affinity within the two gems wasn’t exactly the same, but had some faint differences. One fire burned more orange and one more yellow. He couldn’t fully distinguish the difference, but he did notice one flame seemed more effective against magical constructs, and the other against physical entities.

Jake would replicate that duality by making one gem focus on the destructive aspect of his arcane affinity, and the other on the stable variant. Coming together, they would form his “true” affinity. Granted, he couldn’t make them entirely one or the other, as the explosive variant would be so unstable it would go boom instantly, and the stable would be so nonreactive it became immovable, so he had to find a balance.

Laying his hands upon the bow, he didn’t delay. He placed one hand on each of the gems to inject mana directly into those. His mana snaked its way into it as he examined the entire bow’s structure one final time. He affirmed his existing goal and began. His hands began glowing with Touch of the Malefic Viper as he poured his will into the bow, and without even thinking, he did something more.

His presence descended in a small area around him as he infused it with mana, pressing down on the bow. Ultimately, Touch of the Malefic Viper was about transmuting something by corrupting it in the way you willed, so Pride did make it slightly more effective. How much more effective, he didn’t know, but every little bit counted.

Jake pressed his mana into the bow and began feeling the changes. The flames fought back, but his arcane was superior at every step. The bow began glowing pink-purple as it changed, and the veins on the wood were now no longer glowing like embers.

When he got to the part that was the Ember Arrow skill, Jake found a bit more of a challenge. It fought and struggled as he attempted to forcibly change it. It was a losing battle for the bow, as Jake wasn’t in a rush. No, he was not in a rush at all. He slowly withered it down with the help of his high mana regeneration, the Pylon, and his mask. Jake would play the long game to be safe.

An hour or so later, Jake consumed a mana potion to keep going.

He repeated this for the next half a day as the bow underwent more changes. This was his hardest transmutation so far by quite a bit. At least on a technical level, it was. But he had come a long way. He constantly adapted, and whenever he had issues, he was instantly able to spot another opening or opportunity to exploit. His ability to see all the mana move at once was a massive advantage, courtesy of his insane Perception and equally insane level of energy control.

The result was obvious from the start, and it was only a matter of time. Thirteen and a half hours after he began the transmutation, Jake got the notification of success.

He went straight for Identify, hoping everything had gone as he hoped.

[Bow of Scorched Arcane (Epic)] – A bow made from an unknown type of wood that has now undergone a transformation as dense, arcane energy permeates the bow’s body. Even after its transformation, the brilliance of the bowyer is still evident. The bow’s structure is resilient yet flexible, the string near unbreakable for anyone below C-grade, and the two gemstones passively absorb and transform mana into that of arcane affinity. One gem will primarily create stable arcane mana, and the other, unstable. All Arcane Hunter’s Arrows shot using this bow will be amplified by this arcane mana. The two gemstones can be emptied of energy to release a large burst of arcane mana in the form of a giant arrow that explodes on impact, scorching the plains below with the wrath of your arcana. Enchantments: Arcane Hunter’s Arrows Amplification. Arcane-Scorched Plains.

Requirements: Lvl 120+ in any humanoid race. Quasi-Soulbound.

Jake just smiled and chuckled a bit to himself. Everything was coming out nicely. He had even gotten a level.

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 126 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake inspected the new bow. It had changed quite a bit in the looks department. The red lines were now all pulsing pink-purple. The top gem was almost entirely pink, and the other a dark purple. He could practically feel the arcane mana pulse out of it, and he was more than satisfied.

It had been a good day. Two new weapons had been acquired, both of them great. Now, all he had left was a grind to consume as many elixirs as possible in the stats he wanted before the Treasure Hunt, and he was golden. He also had the token to upgrade the boots, but he was still level 127 in his race, so he wanted to wait for at least one more level. Besides, it wasn’t like anyone was in a rush to upgrade them.

With all of that in mind, Jake tossed his bow in his inventory and entered another alchemy trance as the Treasure Hunt grew ever closer.